□+33617345157 | ✓ vincent.micheli@unige.ch | ♠ vmicheli.github.io

## About

I am a PhD student in the Machine Learning Group at the University of Geneva. My advisor is François Fleuret and my research is supported by the Swiss NSF. I am currently focused on solving complex environments with World Models and Deep Reinforcement Learning.

# **Education**

#### **PhD in Deep Reinforcement Learning**

Geneva, Switzerland

University of Geneva

January 2021 - December 2024

- Research centered around World Models, Deep RL, Transformers, Autoencoders.
- Reviewer for NeurIPS, ICLR and ICML.
- Head TA for 11X001 Introduction to programming and algorithms.
- Head TA for 13X005 Artificial Intelligence: principles and methods.

MsC in Data Science

Lausanne, Switzerland

ÉCOLE POLYTECHNIQUE FÉDÉRALE DE LAUSANNE (EPFL)

September 2018 - September 2020

September 2015 - September 2018

• Relevant coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Natural Language Processing, Time Series, Data Analysis.

#### **BsC in Computer Science and Communication Systems**

Lausanne, Switzerland

ÉCOLE POLYTECHNIQUE FÉDÉRALE DE LAUSANNE (EPFL)

· Relevant coursework: Stochastic Models, Linear Models, Database Systems, Functional Programming.

# Professional Experience\_

Microsoft Research Montreal, Canada

INCOMING RESEARCH SCIENTIST INTERN

May 2023 - August 2023

· Research internship in Deep Reinforcement Learning.

Illuin TechnologyParis, FranceRESEARCH INTERNFebruary 2020 - August 2020

- Led research efforts on the development of efficient (fast, small, multi-task) language models.
- Built a library to train, evaluate, and deploy new models in industrial applications.
- Communicated about our work in several blog posts.

# Selected Papers\_

#### **Transformers are Sample-Efficient World Models**

ICLR 2023 (Top 5%), NeurIPS DRLW 2022 (Best paper)

VINCENT MICHELI, ELOI ALONSO, FRANÇOIS FLEURET

### MineRL Diamond 2021 Competition: Overview, Results, and Lessons Learned

PMLR NeurIPS Competitions, 2022

Anssi Kanervisto, Stephanie Milani, [...], Vincent Micheli, [...]

## **Language Models are Few-Shot Butlers**

EMNLP, 2021

VINCENT MICHELI AND FRANÇOIS FLEURET

# On the importance of pre-training data volume for compact language models

EMNLP, 2020

VINCENT MICHELI, MARTIN D'HOFFSCHMIDT, FRANÇOIS FLEURET

#### Multi-task Reinforcement Learning with a Planning Quasi-Metric

NeurIPS DRLW, 2020

VINCENT MICHELI, KARTHIGAN SINNATHAMBY, FRANÇOIS FLEURET